=====================================

GeekTyrant Privacy Policy
=========================

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit and read [https://geektyrant.com](https://geektyrant.com/) (the "**Site**" , "**Website**", "**GeekTyrant**") from Geek Tyrant Industries, LLC.

### Mediavine Programmatic Advertising (Ver 1.1)

The Website works with Mediavine to manage third-party interest-based advertising appearing on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use first and third-party cookies. A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device (referred to in this policy as a “device”) by the web server so that a website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the Website.

First party cookies are created by the website that you are visiting. A third-party cookie is frequently used in behavioral advertising and analytics and is created by a domain other than the website you are visiting. Third-party cookies, tags, pixels, beacons and other similar technologies (collectively, “Tags”) may be placed on the Website to monitor interaction with advertising content and to target and optimize advertising. Each internet browser has functionality so that you can block both first and third-party cookies and clear your browser’s cache. The "help" feature of the menu bar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to receive notification of new cookies, how to disable existing cookies and how to clear your browser’s cache. For more information about cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information at [All About Cookies](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/).

Without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of the Website content and features. Please note that rejecting cookies does not mean that you will no longer see ads when you visit our Site. In the event you opt-out, you will still see non-personalized advertisements on the Website.

The Website collects the following data using a cookie when serving personalized ads:

* IP Address
* Operating System type
* Operating System version
* Device Type
* Language of the website
* Web browser type
* Email (in hashed form)

Mediavine Partners (companies listed below with whom Mediavine shares data) may also use this data to link to other end user information the partner has independently collected to deliver targeted advertisements. Mediavine Partners may also separately collect data about end users from other sources, such as advertising IDs or pixels, and link that data to data collected from Mediavine publishers in order to provide interest-based advertising across your online experience, including devices, browsers and apps. This data includes usage data, cookie information, device information, information about interactions between users and advertisements and websites, geolocation data, traffic data, and information about a visitor’s referral source to a particular website. Mediavine Partners may also create unique IDs to create audience segments, which are used to provide targeted advertising.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit [National Advertising Initiative opt out page](https://thenai.org/opt-out/). You may also visit [Digital Advertising Alliance website](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/) and [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#) to learn more information about interest-based advertising. You may download the AppChoices app at [Digital Advertising Alliance’s AppChoices app](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices) to opt out in connection with mobile apps, or use the platform controls on your mobile device to opt out.

For specific information about Mediavine Partners, the data each collects and their data collection and privacy policies, please visit [Mediavine Partners](https://www.mediavine.com/ad-partners/).

### Common ID Cookie

This site uses cookies and similar tracking technologies such as the Common ID cookie to provide its services. Cookies are important devices for measuring advertising effectiveness and ensuring a robust online advertising industry. The Common ID cookie stores a unique user id in the first party domain and is accessible to our ad partners. This simple ID that can be utilized to improve user matching, especially for delivering ads to iOS and MacOS browsers. Users can opt out of the Common ID tracking cookie by clicking [here](#opt-out).

### Advertising Privacy Settings

FOR EU USERS ONLY: When you use our site, pre-selected companies may access and use certain information on your device and about your interests to serve ads or personalized content. You may revisit or change consent-choices at any time by clicking [here](#cmp).

### Personal Information We Collect

When you visit GeekTyrant, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse GeekTyrant, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the GeekTyrant, and information about how you interact with the GeekTyrant. We refer to this automatically-collected information as "**Device Information**."

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

* "**Cookies**" are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
    
* "**Log files**" track actions occurring on the GeekTyrant, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.
    
* "**Web beacons**," "**tags**," and "**pixels**" are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the GeekTyrant.

When we talk about "Personal Information" in this Privacy Policy, we are talking both about Device Information.

### How Do We Use Your Personal Information?

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our readers browse and interact with the GeekTyrant.)

Sharing Your Personal Information
---------------------------------

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above. We also use **Google Analytics** to help us understand how our readers use the Site -- you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here [https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). You can also opt-out of **Google Analytics** here [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We also use **ChartBeat Analytics** you can read more about how **ChartBeat** uses your Personal Information here [https://chartbeat.com/privacy/](https://chartbeat.com/privacy/). You can also opt-out of ChatBeat Analytics here [https://static.chartbeat.com/opt-out.html](https://static.chartbeat.com/opt-out.html)

**Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful requests for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.**

Ads
---

Third-party advertisers on GeekTyrant may collect tracking information in a different manner that is set out in this Privacy Policy. The only information that they will be able to track is basic Website usage information; e-mail addresses are not passed on to advertisers for any reason even if they are provided to GeekTyrant voluntarily.

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the **Network Advertising Initiative**’s ( "**NAI**") educational page at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work](http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work).

**You can opt out of targeted advertising at:**  
**FaceBook** - [https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads)  
**Google** - [https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous)  
**Bing** - [https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads](https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads)

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the **Digital Advertising Alliance**’s opt-out portal at [http://optout.aboutads.info/](http://optout.aboutads.info/) and the **NAI**'s opt-out portal at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt\_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

Do Not Track
------------

Please note that we do not alter our GeekTyrant's data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

Retention & Security
--------------------

Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage third-party service providers. By using the Website, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, which may have different data protection rules than in your country. While such information is outside of Canada, it is subject to the laws of the country in which it is held and may be subject to disclosure to the governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of such other country, pursuant to the laws of such country. However, our practices regarding your personal information will at all times continue to be governed by this Privacy Policy and, if applicable, we will comply with the **General Data Protection Regulation** ( "**GDPR**") requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of personal information from the EU/EEA to the third country.

We have implemented various physical, administrative and technical safeguards designed to protect the confidentiality and security of Personal Information under our control. However, no security measures are absolute or wholly guaranteed.

We will maintain your Personal Information for as long as a business need exists, or as required by applicable laws, regulations, or government orders.

Rights
------

On written request and subject to proof of identity, you may access the Personal Information that we hold, and ask that any necessary corrections be made, where applicable, as authorized or required by law. However, to make sure that the Personal Information we maintain about you is accurate and up to date, please inform us immediately of any change in your Personal Information.

Under the **GDPR**, you may be entitled to additional rights, including (**i**) the right to withdraw consent to processing where consent is the basis of processing; (**ii**) the right to access your Personal Information and certain other supplementary information, under certain conditions; (**iii**) the right to object to unlawful data processing, under certain conditions; (**iv**) the right to erasure of Personal Information about you, under certain conditions; (**v**) the right to demand that we restrict processing of your Personal Information, under certain conditions, if you believe we have exceeded the legitimate basis for processing, processing is no longer necessary, are processing, or believe your personal information is inaccurate; (**vi**) the right to data portability of Personal Information concerning you that you provided us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format, under certain conditions; (**vii**) the right object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you, under certain conditions; (**viii**) the right to lodge a complaint with data protection authorities. If you want to learn more about your rights under the **GDPR**, you can visit the European Commission’s page on Data Protection at [http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/index\_en.htm](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/index_en.htm).

Changes
-------

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

Contact Us
----------

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by e-mail at [tyrant@geektyrant.com](mailto:tyrant@geektyrant.com) or [geek@geektyrant.com](mailto:geek@geektyrant.com)

\[Last Updated February 24th, 2021\]
